welcome to saturday roundtable
where we talk about our projects what
we've been up to and
what we could use help with if there is
anything who would like to start
i can go ahead and start um
so my main project is goalie bot
i'm saying that rather than reason score
just because
i think he's easier to explain so uh
goaliebot is a
online personality that builds mass
agreement
by helping helping people understand
each other and understanding the
evidence behind what they believe
so he builds a mass agreement
uh um have not made any progress i've
been moving
um although jubilee i wanted to see if
you would
give me an introduction to those guys on
youtube that interviewed you
several weeks ago
so i can introduce you to jared jared i
know more than he's come to a few
solutions
yep absolutely yeah that'd be nice i'm
sure i could just reach out to him but
it's nice with an intro um
uh so it'd be good to be interviewed on
their podcast and get my cap rating for
my project
um i think that's what they called a cap
anyways
uh and then uh
yeah i was going to do some stuff with
the la with the us election
but it's coming up really fast so i
don't think it will do anything else
effective and then
there's several other similar projects
in the area of
sense making and decision collaborative
collective action really is there's a
good term for it um
through open global mind canonical
debate lab society
library a choice society library and
open global miner both
trying to find the funding for some
projects that they would need some
developers so i could do that
adriel might have some work for me in
the future um
so hey so yeah so there's lots of
options i'm in the game game a
thing where i'm gonna need to make some
money at some point i'm starting to now
but i need to kind of figure out long
term how i'm gonna
feed and clothe myself so
that's that's where i'm at i don't i
don't really need any help except from
jubilee and unless anyone wants to
has something they need like an
explainer video for that's something
that
a goalie bought a reason score would be
helpful or if you
the most helpful thing was if you knew
someone else that
you had a disagreement with that'd be
kind of
not like climate change although it
could be but something smaller and that
seems at least partially fact-based
isn't all opinion
like who's the best star war character
or something like that
um would be a bad example
but something that real world if if you
could think of someone that you have a
debate with and this would it'd be good
if i had
two people that would be willing to use
my tool to
uh make that decision together or come
to an agreement
so that's it for me
i just needed to say something and then
i was like oh god that means i'm next
uh i will and then i forgot what i was
going to say when i needed um
my projects are solution raising which
is an hour-long conversation regenerate
adjacent possible solutions we could
implement now with ten thousand people
and a hundred thousand dollars
and we held our solution raising last
week on humor i don't know what we're
going to hold it on this week i haven't
decided yet
my other project is meta learning magic
and we are starting our first six week
course on tuesday i have there's five of
us all together there's one spot left if
i happen to find someone
applicable who wants to to come and
create uh crowdsource solutions to our
own lives so
we're going to be dealing with health
relationships time and resources on four
different weeks and then holding a
solution raising
to better solve one of those things and
then introducing people to how we can
grow this structure to ten thousand
people
who are going to put in twenty five
dollars a month so we have a ton of
resources
and we can retire people from gay media
game b and so that's what i
put up to this past week is just
starting the six week course putting it
out there
being like right it doesn't need to be
perfect it's just about inviting the
people i feel comfortable enough with
that it doesn't need to be perfect which
is perfect it's game b people
and trying that process and seeing how
it works and then improving it together
and i also don't i don't think i have
anything
i need help with at the moment just
attending that six week course myself
will be enough i just need to also learn
how to feed and clothe myself but
without money i need to look like
how do i actually put food on the table
that is delicious and nutritious
and so that is what i will be dealing
with first in the six week course
and i will absolutely be introducing you
to jared from upgrading society
i can do that as well all right who's
next
i guess i can go next because i assume
that vincent's going last because i
think he's
he's in the hot seat all right uh my
project is converati
uh it's meant to be an in a source of
information that earns your trust
um it's also i guess
a partner project to wiki election which
has
for for the most part been my project up
until now but now
election is just sort of a part of uh on
friday
been working with uh one of the other
people that shows up to these meetings
uh either going by radic or
matush on the prototype for wiki
election
um that's been up still waiting on the
final version of that
but while i'm working on that i've been
working on the specs for
the prototype for conferrati where um
the next step is probably
it's going to be a platform to help
build what i'm calling portals like
wikilection where it's sort of
information sites that would share
from the same root information source uh
so i've been working on the specs for
that
uh and when that's ready then i'll
probably be working with bentley and
reddick to
help manage some developers probably in
india or
in just you know hired on upwork
uh to start coding the platform and
that's where i'm at
all right is it my turn
so right now i'm working on a project
called catalyst
um and recently i made some significant
progress in last few weeks
the the problem that the platform is
solving is
information overload specifically and
also
um not enough how i see it actionable
information
on traditional social media platforms
and so even i myself
have been like with quarantine and not
being
doing my things and spending a lot more
screen time on like facebook
and instagram and like that just
scrolling
um and there is a definite like
addicting
quality to like the reward system of
scrolling but i
do it because i want it connected to
some sort of actual information things i
could do
ways i can help people ways i can impact
the world
new things that i might that might help
me in my personal life
and so the idea is basically creating a
platform where instead of
an algorithm determining what you are
seeing you
basically set out intention in what sort
of information resources people you want
to get connected with
and when you go on the platform it
basically um
through a series of filters lets you
filter your own
and create your kind of own feeds and
right now obviously that's a big
undertaking so my initial prototype that
i just finished
has basically the capability to go into
different
um rooms which are basically like
fellowship room
project room startup funding room
and then within those rooms there's
hundreds of each type
of that information and you can filter
and sort them by five different metrics
right now
i'm using webflow so it's a no code
solution and
webflow has like a limit of five
multi-reference fields and so
um you can filter by location by the
person like
is this useful for an entrepreneur
someone of faith
um by the type of information the
topic and also the room that it's in
um so i just got the filtering
capability finished
and i also have a prototype of the site
that i'm still kind of
working on the ui i'm looking for a
little help just kind of like on
feedback with the design before i start
kind of like going into beta testing
because i know it's not there yet and
the other thing is i'm looking for some
help just like
with the data collection and cleaning up
side
there would there are some like scripts
i'm looking to write that would
speed that process up a lot um in terms
of like taking information and just
re-ordering it in other ways so that way
it's easier for me
because i've been collecting like the
first like 2 000 posts
myself and they're very rich in terms of
the data but it takes a lot of time
and i'm going through going through my
tab i have like
a thousand one tabs open and i'm gonna
be kind of like
putting those all into the database and
like categorizing everything so it's
really easy to search and filter through
for anyone
awesome and you'd mentioned uh maybe you
and i swapping some time
so i can kind of help you out on those
scripts
probably the easiest way to do that if
you want to just find some time
on my calendar bentleydavis.com
schedule or if you go to
bentleydavis.com there's a schedule
button
yeah i think that we've done that before
right did we
yeah yeah um uh
and we might even want to go ahead and
record it and post it on here if you're
doing open development that way other
people can see what it's like to
collaborate in in game b
projects and do time swapping um
i definitely would want you to kind of
look at goaliebot and reason score and
just give your
your feedback in general and then your
business um
business feedback on maybe you can help
me brainstorm on different funding
or sustainability you know markets or
stuff like that so
yeah that'd be great i would love to do
it kind of like live when i'm with you
so i can give you my like immediate
feedback yeah yeah that'd be great uh
cool
um uh so jubilee invited you to also be
on the hot seat is there anything that
that we as a group could work with you
on if you want to do a demo of what you
have so far and get our immediate
feedback would be something
sure um yeah let me think about
so for the hot seat what do you guys
typically uh what what is the typical
end goal yeah so it's it's just an
opportunity for
anyone to ask for help on their project
so it's very varied um so it's really
whatever the individual needs
um and honestly we haven't a lot of
times we haven't had someone on the hot
seat because all of us kind of know what
we're doing on our project and
didn't really need any help so we
haven't done it a lot but
it could definitely be anything that
that you would you would find valuable
having
undivided attention of three other
people okay
so that sounds good um in that case i
think the two questions that
um i would want to kind of revolve it
around would be like
one um in the current design
is this is the information like
understandable in
in this way um that would be the first
one and the second one
is is something like this valuable
enough that would
consider spending time on it
instead of being on a social platform
which is a lot more like
alive so to say um
like and you know if so is it something
that would be worth
like paying for in any regards those are
kind of like assumptions that i'm trying
to test right now
excellent all right so i have not screen
shared on this yet so give me a second
it's just down at the bottom if you can
see the little tabs mute stop cam
there's one that says share screen and
then we'll pop it up on them
where the four of us are i have a lot of
tabs open so
well when you when you share a screen if
you're in chrome it'll give you the
option to share it there we go
it so you can put up whatever you want
in there and then i'll put it up on the
screen
okay cool all right so this is the
current site
um i am signed in um this is a home page
so basically um
beginning there's just ways to kind of
like filter through the information so
i'll start with like the highest sort of
category so networks are open spaces for
aggregating
aggregating crowdsourced knowledge so
these could be issues like chronovirus
domains like education
cooperative economics and so within each
one of these
if we go into let's say
entrepreneurship
so each
each domain has its own sort of like
homepage
where you can kind of like see the
description
um the rooms that are inside of this
network so these are like the specific
types of information that are in it so
startup funding
career change and hackathons and then i
also have
a youtube playlist that's embedded in
each one
and the idea is making like a
crowdsourced
youtube playlist for each one of these
topics that anyone can add to and submit
to from the site
so we can kind of create like a
knowledge base of like the best
videos for each one of these domains
so within the rooms if you're signed in
as a member you can also like
save and unsave different rooms
and you can also follow or unfollow
different networks
and once you do that also have members
that are inside of these and you can see
kind of like the members profile
so going into the room so i'll go into
startup funding because this is one that
i kind of populated with the most
information thus far
so this is basically
the card view so i'm working on the
layout a little bit because there's a
lot
even even a lot more information that's
kind of on these cards right now
which i have on each one of these
opportunities
so these are all different funding
sources and
you can either change the view so for
example
going to map view and now you get all
these resources on
a map
and you kind of open them up
individually or you can switch back to
the card view
and then also have search functionality
which i'm not sure exactly
how to prompt this but you can kind of
search by almost anything
that's in the card so for example new
york this is like all the
funding opportunities accelerators
capital incubators that are in new york
and you can also filter it by type
so let's say you want capital focus
and it'll show you like how many results
for each one
and you can reset the filters um
obviously a hard part of this was like
getting the filters to not be insane
because there's like 300 countries
so for each room it has like a
customizable
set of filters that that make it like
not very overwhelming for the user
um and then you also have like a post
functionality where you can post
into this room
i'll stop there so far if anyone wants
to jump in with anything
or tell me where to go next is that a
quick question at the moment when you
say i could post in here does that mean
it becomes a card or does it become
something else
yes so the idea is if these are all
crowd source knowledge bases that anyone
can add to
um and so i don't have it set up yet but
basically when you post
it'll have a little form and it'll have
all the fields specific to this
uh this room and then you can add to it
and when you add to it you would also
get
points um and the idea that i'm trying
to
kind of flesh out right now is that
there's like a commons
of knowledge and when you add to the
commons of knowledge you kind of have
you like almost have ownership over a
certain percentage of the knowledge and
as it grows
obviously your percentage decreases but
um there will be some sort of value
that you might receive back um
from the network if you are an owner of
knowledge that's on the
comments basically
so i i'm trying to think because i i
think i got a little
mis and you've showed this to me before
i think but i
i think i've completely forgotten it
since she last showed it to me so i'm
kind of like coming in fresh
um i thought that it was a feed
which implies new information coming in
but really this is a knowledge commons
right so this one is actually i kind of
change it up like it's catalyst
directory and so
this is like all of the um information
that is on the site and it's not as much
as a feed it's more of like
you have an intention to find something
and you can go here and find it
however um
there is a dashboard page um
where i'm starting to work on more of a
feed it's a little more complicated to
do this with no code
um so the feed right now is
you have all of the different joined
rooms and networks
you can see all of your like saved posts
and then what i'm also working on is
notification so for example if you
say i want to like i want to save this
or notif
be notified for this startup accelerator
because i just missed the deadline
and i want to know when it's open again
for next year
um i'm trying to kind of help people
stay on top of and manage opportunities
so that could be a fellowship that only
happens once a year an accelerator uh
an event a sort of like volunteer
opportunity
um so trying to help people kind of like
stay on top of notification so basically
as like
something that you're following gets
updated in terms of like the date
then it would show up here um so yeah i
don't have like a traditional
feed yet um
but that's something that i hope to
develop potentially in the next
prototype which is not
a no code um yeah i mean the the other
thing that i can do
is based off of the information that's
in someone's profile it's kind of like a
work around
um but let's see
so when you go to someone's profile you
can basically
you can see like the things that they
submitted you also have the capability
to see the things that
passively match the attributes in their
profile
so real quick i'll show you guys what
the kind of like fursonas look like
so like facebook kind of like
automatically puts you in these like
kind of buckets
of like we think that you're this type
of person and they try to like
tag you and all these um
basically things to like show you
relevant ads
and so the idea is obviously in a
platform where we're not collecting
data and selling it it is up to you to
basically tell the platform like
what kind of stuff you want to see so
for example
um if you consider yourself a gamer
then you can kind of subscribe to this
gamer tag
you could go here and just look at all
the resources for gamer it'll show you
like all the new ones
or so this is kind of like a reddit like
a subreddit or
you can when you're making your profile
like check off like i'm a farmer
i am a systems thinker i am spiritual
and
it'll base your feed eventually will
kind of like show you the information
that has
been recently added that matches these
things
as well as the other things in your
profile like which
rooms you joined which um and which
networks you're in
so a couple of thoughts uh one is an
interesting challenge with knowledge um
repositories or commons is
making sure well is knowing when
things are up to date because often they
get stale pretty quick
yeah and then also a process of keeping
things up to date i even
often frustrated by blo like i'm in the
technical space so
often someone do a blog post about using
a technology but they won't mention what
version the tech was
and of course in you know a month later
that could be um
wrong um so at least having the date
that the content was
created the date it was last updated
and then uh and of course you've kind of
maxed out your filters in this
technology but being able to
filter on that and wait for people to
either
update it or it's even more important
than whether or not it's updated it's
just when someone looked at it
and made sure it's still correct right
the last time it was kind of checked
would be something nice and maybe even
have things if they weren't checked
after a certain amount of time and that
may vary by group
like tech it'll happen a lot faster but
if you're talking about
sustainability processes you know those
don't change
those don't go out of date they're kind
of evergreen so exactly
but yes something for just future is
giving some sort of visibility into how
stale the information might be and maybe
hiding it after a certain amount that
would be something you have to consider
or manage by group um but yeah i think
that's really important part because
there's a lot of places out there where
you go in and these knowledge commons
just haven't been kept up to date
which is understandable um but it's nice
to know when it happens
right so the current the current let me
know what you think about this
i was considering kind of having it
where like if you upload a resource
then you would put a date
when that resource like you kind of
guarantee it fresh until it's like the
actual you know it's like the expiration
date for you
oh yeah so i have it by by item that's
interesting right so each item
if you upload the item you are the best
one to say like
this is a project it's probably going to
change in three weeks or this is like a
tool kit it's been here for 10 years
i've been using it it's probably going
to be here for another two years
and so then once that date passes then
you kind of get a notification
where it's like almost your
responsibility to help keep
things updated and if it's not updated
within a certain time period then it'll
kind of get
uh archived on the site until somebody
else
updates it or verifies that it's updated
um so that was the kind of
current scheme that i had especially for
projects that was important like keeping
projects up to date
the idea is like if you submit your own
project
then you put a deadline in which that
project is no longer visible
and you get an email sent to you
automatically saying hey we're taking
your project down unless you can verify
that it's still up to date
or update it and that's actually what i
need help with on the scripting is
pre-filling form so that people don't
have to like redo the entire post
but they basically like pull the
information from the previous post into
a new form
to like update it yeah i think that's
good
um i'd i'd also like to have it to where
people can
other people can come in and say it's
dale because i i know
if i there's a big temptation if it's
your own project to just put it like 10
years out and then
of course the project fails and no one
knows you don't go back
because you're so depressed when it
doesn't work out um
uh so yeah so also i i i think that's an
interesting idea for people kind of
saying how evergreen it is
but as long as we maybe when possible
it was a feature feature have a tour
people can also kind of say i think this
is stale
or like i you know i went and tried to
follow it and it's broken here and
it's different here and stuff like that
um that would be helpful but yeah i
hadn't that's a good idea to have it by
item
it's interesting
yeah because yeah sometimes things are
evergreen sometimes but not
yeah i've already had stuff on this site
where i'm like oh no the link broke
since i had it great
like it's been a month
can you for projects is that
go to projects actually this is an
experiment of like a pinterest board
view um
right now but um eventually
basically i have each information type
has
um i don't think no i can't switch tabs
so each type of each post has the
following kind of like main categories
of information
it's either a resource
or like a tool it's an event which can
go on a calendar
it's an opportunity which an opportunity
could be like
a an offer it could be a request it
could be
it's something that's a little bit more
time sensitive like an event
but it's something that can be like
attached to other things so like a
project can have multiple opportunities
a resource could have an opportunity
um and then there's projects which i
don't have
any projects on the site right now
because i didn't want to have lots of
people's like personal information on
here until i like
secure it i have some in air table that
i've
of friends that have projects that are
looking for help
um and then saved are actually all the
the ones that specific to my login i've
saved so far
so there's just um in what you're saying
all posts sounds like
it's media like it's like all posts
don't actually include all posts because
events opportunities and projects
aren't in all posts uh they do i just
don't have many events
opportunities and projects live on the
site i just kind of put a few up to test
okay so these are four distinct things
or everything fits under all posts
everything fits under all posts there is
another category that i haven't added
here which is like basically
resources tools which is basically most
of
what everything is right now so when i
go to projects
those are projects that i've said yes i
want to follow in some way whether
that's because i want an opportunity
like
there's opportunities i actually want to
do in it or it's my project and i want
other people to do opportunities
or i just want to watch what's going on
in it is there a way to distinguish
between those
levels of my involvement as the user
yes so that's so this like
this tab is only um
only posts that have been saved could
also have only projects that have been
saved
only events that have been saved that's
kind of just like a
condition so i guess i'm i'm trying to
figure out if this stuff should be
in like the dashboard um where it's like
this is everything you have saved and
then you can like sub categorize it by
the
the type of information it is or
if you go to that page was basically
like
all the posts on the site i wanted to
kind of be able to like jump in and just
see what's
on here and then see like the different
types
um but i also added another little tab
so you can kind of like quickly see like
you know if i go and save um
then it'll show up here
i don't know if this helps because i'm
not i'm not a tech person i can't even
do no code solutions
but to me it seems if i'm under projects
i want what i've saved to be at the top
like the more relevant i've made it the
more i want it at the top as opposed to
game a where they put the mo
who's paid them by the sponsors at the
top to have like
who i'm sponsoring like these are the
ones that i'm dedicated to
and so if i'm that i want to be able to
i want both i want to be able to see
what i've saved and see everything that
i've saved it's like the full picture
but
but more importantly if i'm in
opportunities i want to see the
opportunities that i've said in projects
and events that i've said are most
important at the top right like
right like personalized sponsorship i
don't know but that's what's coming up
for me
i'll let the more techy people give more
feedback on the stuff you actually asked
about
so now that is a good question though is
like what order in which these should
show up
um right now the default is
it's shown up by the number of um
saves that a post has by default
so collectively we've decided this one's
more important than this one as opposed
to i've decided that i care more about
acoustic neuromas than diabetes but
there's more people with diabetes than
acoustic neuroma
i mean but i have had acoustic neuroma
which is why i would care about it more
like that
that level so i guess if i create like a
feed
page the order would be like um
time based like if it was just uploaded
it's going to kind of show up in the top
maybe um in the like all posts right now
with popularity
and then in your posts um i don't know
how to sort it
um so i yeah let me
pipe in here and talk about my
philosophy it's funny my my philosophy
i've always
uh said or last couple months what i've
been thinking about this is that it
deals with feeds but
it also i just realized listening to
this that it deals with sorting on just
like any display page
so ideally and this is a lot of text so
this may not be
short term but people should be able to
choose
their what algorithm is used to
sort the display or to sort a feed
and it'd be one of the things i've been
thinking of is just a general tool
that lets you not just
choose an algorithm but have a library a
public library that people can
contribute
algorithms and then and then choose from
and use them in case they're not
technical
um and then some you know general simple
things so
yeah like in order
so if you have a filter and then you
have a time base that's probably
okay unless the data gets so big that
it depends on how narrow you want to
narrow it down
um yeah i'd be interested in exploring
other
solutions that can integrate into this
prototype
um as of right now webflow doesn't allow
dynamic sorting
it's only it's like you have to set the
sorting um for each page
and then you can't really change it
unless you add an additional like script
or javascript on top
yeah yeah and then we kind of need to
figure out in the short term what are
the sorts and filters that would be kind
of most
common um because you don't want to
you know we can't expect you to have
this brand new
sorting and filtering library
as part of your project right yeah
and and adrian jubilee if i'm talking
too much i'll just go ahead and jump in
i don't know jubilee yet anymore that
you want to go over before i but i got a
couple more ideas
so i just want one more thing um
in terms i haven't showed you guys the
different like views but i do have a
view which is basically an
air table embed that i have for like
this is like
1300 online free online courses and so
it's a little bit
too much to like upload to the site as
like an individual card
um but within this view you can
obviously use the airtable sorts
and groups and filters which is nice
although i don't like love their
their ui as much as it's not obviously
very customizable
but that is one option i have is to kind
of like use another
um like air table or another um
spreadsheets kind of like
embed with built-in sorting um that's
something i would like to eventually
build but obviously within the no code
version of this that's what i'm doing
and then in terms
of um other ways to
use um i like showed it briefly i
actually just got this working last
night but i have a kumu in bed so
anything that has
a um
plot view i can do like a mind map and
it's all pulling from the same database
but this is a database of all different
fellowships
um and then they're all kind of
connected and categorized by like
different
uh different tags and stuff like that
so you can like for one data set like
kind of switch between the different
card plot lists
different views
that's all i want to add that
uh so uh have you run across uh the
group called
open global mind yet yes i
i'm planning on joining their next
meeting
it's very very dense and i'm excited to
be a part of it but i was like i'm not
ready yet
yeah yeah yeah so they're working on
knowledge commons and stuff some very
similar stuff so
you'll like that i've been attending for
several weeks now
um well several months maybe uh so yeah
so i want to suggest that
and then
oh i had another idea but i've lost it
now
um yeah
yeah i think it's good to your first
questions for us
um would we would we use this and maybe
even would we contribute
to it um as a resource as a
commons that we financially fund
i would be open to both of those
um we've certainly in our own group
tried to
create that we've created three
different versions or four of that
projects piece for things in game b
and then you know maybe even game b
could be a tag
in there if your tech currently allows
for something like that um
yeah and then yeah just
in general as a place to keep up on what
tools and stuff are available
my only concern is that there are a
couple other
things that of course aren't exactly
overlapping
this but do overlap some areas of it
so then it do i have the cognitive time
and
energy to keep this as one of my
resources that fulfill that need
those needs so i'd have to kind of think
about
how this fits in with everything else um
but so it's so the answer is probably
yes
um i don't i don't know if i could
justify paying
i mean i i i contribute to a lot of
things just because i want them to exist
and i use them
so i think that that's good um if like
for my
would it be a business need to pay for
or a you know there's a difference in
the startup community
between a vitamin and medicine right
vitamins
kind of nice that people don't often do
it they kind of want it and then there's
the have to have
um so i think this is kind of in the
vitamin unless you're
unless you're a salesperson or something
and these contacts are extremely
important
um but yeah so those those are both
possibilities and maybe i need to spend
a little time getting in there
and give you more specific um like i did
find it helpful because of this or
i'm missing this right right
like for me with value it depends on
which
part of me is paying for this like as a
project holder
if i was paying like 10 bucks a month um
or whatever for i would want to be
getting volunteers and getting people
like
if that was part marketing then yes i
would be willing to put it in if it was
just to be on a different list
no if as a user it was more like a
patreon where i'm putting 5-10 bucks
towards it and then i get to choose
where that money like it's going to
support
projects and going to create things um
with part of it of course going to do
the site but i don't know
i don't think i would pay for just the
site it would be like the idea
of what that money's going towards with
some going to the site does that make
sense
yeah like i'd want to be involved like
patreon right i'm not paying for patreon
i'm paying for the artists
and then patreon takes money and so
that's in that level is probably where i
would
want to want to want to pay for it okay
it makes sense
hey joel do you have any feedback
um so the is the top
level item for all this what would you
say is projects like that sort of what
most of the information
is is centered around or is it sort of
evenly projects and resources okay so
i guess there's a difference between
what it is now and what i would like it
to be
um so right now the main information
is tools and resources so that is
basically
um you know like really cool
platforms websites toolkits
um things that i've found over the years
that i
was just like wow and then i like very
frequently reference people too
um and that if i didn't you know if i
wasn't crazy about like information
hoarding and like finding all this stuff
that i would have never found that stuff
and then i wouldn't have recommended it
to other people so that's just kind of
like what i have in my back pocket
already
which is how what it's kind of like it's
made on the site
but right now everything on the site is
more or less
um around the idea of social impact and
the
the related fields that are in my mind
most vital to social impact so like
there's nothing here for sports
but there is for cooperative economics
there's nothing in here for like
fashion or like news unless it's like a
very informational news article that
relates to systems design or
sustainability
um and so mostly everything is kind of
centered around
more important issues
um and the idea is that so obviously i
would like to make it free for anyone to
basically go on and like do what you
guys just saw
and kind of like filter through the
information um
but i was thinking of making like a kind
of like a patreon membership tier where
you become a catalyst and
basically the financial contribution
will go towards like growing this
comment so like even if you just like
subscribe and you use it
frequently or occasionally and you can
upload your own things as well
um the money will go towards growing
this so that it's kind of a win-win
you are also helping creating something
that you're a part of
the other part is basically want to
create a reward system for like people
who help contribute to it they will
actually get
like paid out for helping build the
platform
um and the other thing would be to
basically um like i kind of want my
full-time career to be a connector so
like i want to reach out to like the
climate change organizations that i've
found over the last few years and like
ask them like
what are the opportunities you have for
people what help do you need
and how do we kind of like funnel more
energy
and time towards things that already
exist that are good
um and basically making the connections
between
people that otherwise wouldn't happen
when you know you have i look at all
these facebook pages and like
these facebook groups for like you know
climate change organizations they post
like three people like it they're like
asking for something and then other
people post that they're looking for
something and like two people like it
and so like i wonder if they're ever
getting connected and so the idea would
be like
not just me but having eventually a team
of people who are like those connectors
and when you
pay to basically be a member then you
also in your profile basically choose
what things you want to be connected
with
which could match any of the filters
hundreds of tags
locations on the site and then we will
kind of like also
focus efforts on trying to find those
things and basically send like
either customizable like email digest or
pop it in your like notifications
so kind of like also um when you
join the site and you put out your
intentions of what you're looking for
then we kind of start shifting focus to
like what the users need to like
accomplish their individual
goals i would like it to be centered
around kind of like
game b which is why this is like one of
the first places i'm like really sharing
this and i'd like to
make sure that it stays aligned with
that
um but that's that's the the kind of
idea and then obviously
hopefully at that point we'd have more
resources to start building out the sort
of like
passive connection news feed or you know
other systems like that
i see so when you save resources that's
in essence is that referring to like
not individual website but kind of where
it might be like the website for
um uh start
a startup accelerator or something like
that or it could also be like
an a news site like cnn.com might be
a resource not the individual articles
but just the site
right where the articles are hosted
prepare my air table so you guys can
kind of see into the madness if you'd
like
um
so basically and
if this is confusing i would love to um
get feedback on that but so how i have
it right now is so there's post types
um the main post types as i
kind of previously mentioned are events
offers
organizations projects request
resources individuals which is like a
user and then
discussion which i don't know if i want
that but that's it's there
um so if i go to all types
and i group these by the type
type
so basically there are like subtypes
like
for example startup accelerator is like
a subtype of funding but it is also a
resource
um an organization has subtype so like
you could be a non-profit
design network activist group and then i
have
tool type which are tools are resources
so design tool database
chrome plug-in systems mapping tool
and then the other things like you
mentioned like so there's
content which is
more of like this is an article or a
book
or a show or a movie like kind of like
one singular
piece of content that you can kind of
consume and then a resource would be
like
netflix is a resource because it has
multiple pieces of content
on it a visualization website is a
resource
a an aggregation website a wiki um
a google form a database so like
basically i have
it very um broadly categorized right now
as something that helps people
um achieve a goal and and that is not
um as like
it's not as specific as a piece of
content
so uh i'm not familiar enough with our
table yet
um can something exist in
two of those categories and
subcategories at the same time
so each post has a main type and then it
has
um other types so you kind of pick like
what is the main thing that this is
and that one gets kind of like displayed
on the card because i don't want to have
like 10 things being displayed right
so there's a main code type and then
everything has a subtype and you can
actually see like
these are the posts of the
so these are all the posts that are of
the main type so like visualization
website
strategic intelligence is a post that
is the main thing it's a visualization
website
and then you can see the room that it's
in
and you also see the link of like a list
nomad list
listopia book list like it's the
secondary
list as well so uh
something maybe to consider for the
future unless it's
too complex is kind of a
graph ontology or a hierarchical
ontology
or tagging system because
sometimes things do fit in multiple
places
and also you want to put it in a very
specific place
but if someone searches for a more
general thing like if someone's looking
for a systems
uh diagramming system it's also a
resource and maybe when you attach
to the systems the syst the um
the application knows that it's uh
the system thinking the application
automatically knows it's closer to these
things so if they search for that then
it'll find
the near neighbors um that's
something just in general i've been
thinking about on how to organize that
data and of course
airtable's not designed for that webflow
is not designed for that
um so that would be something
interesting to work on that is
a very interesting um problem
that the way i've been working around it
for now is
so within the posts um there's obviously
the different rooms and so i kind of
have it like
sub cap the forms are sub categorized
so for example this is like the um
update project form and so the product
form already has specific
fields like filled out basically
and so when you submit a project you
can't like make it
a piece of content accidentally so it
obviously reduces the time that a user
needs to spend
but it also helps the cat organization
so if you're in the project room and you
hit submit
it's automatically going to know you're
trying to submit a project and like give
you that form
um so i'm kind of hesitant to create
like
a general form but i did want to share
one thing with you guys i don't know if
it's going to pop up right now
um but this is how i've been collecting
the information that i'd also like to
figure out how to scale this to mobile
and also like let other people use it
okay
all right so here is a resource called
the d-school reading list so let's say i
wanted to add this to catalyst
um i have this little web clipper
um and i click
post and so it pulls the the post title
um i can kind of clean up a bit the url
and then i'll go in and i'll
kind of grab logo from the page if there
is one
and if there's not then i will just
screenshot the logo
and then for the cover you can add like
a
page screenshot
and then i'll basically say like okay
this is like a reading list so this
should go
in the educational resources
let's type main is a
[Music]
i would say resource list and then i can
also say like
book
um and then the topics so you can select
like a main topic
and other topics um so for example
this would be like design
design thinking and so the buckets would
be like who is this
for so like this is for designers
um and then you can also put like
organization locations which i'm just
going to put online
and then if you wanted to you can add
new
drop downs that weren't over here so you
can like add a different a new topic a
new location a new room
um and i'm just going to add this to the
design network
so i hit add and then that's going to
show up
on airtable and i could also have it
from there automatically show up on the
site
and then it has the pictures and all the
tags and so that's how i've been like
basically doing the categorization
right now of everything is through that
but the only thing is i can't do that on
mobile
and i i would like to build maybe even
like a
like a really quick cheap like mobile
app that lets me do that because i have
so many tabs
phone from facebook from slack that i'm
like oh i want to save this for later
because i don't really need it now but i
want to be able to find it later
and so i want like a better bookmark gap
where i can share to app
and then do that and be able to
categorize everything with that level of
like detail
um and have it kind of like upload to
the site automatically get points for it
as a contributor to the commons
etc etc
yeah yeah i don't know if there's any
real simple
easy to do mobile app to do that
so there's some existing apps where you
can you can share to it no just make a
note of the
url and then later you could do the data
entry
but that would be the data entry the
phone i know that you can take a website
now
and and have it accept shares from other
apps on the phone including the browser
yeah so there's a web
tech to do that but um
i don't know it still would take a fair
amount of work
to set that up and then would it be
really easy for the user
to make it really easy for the user you
need to get it into the app stores
so um like you could develop an ionic
app and stuff like that but it it would
you know
it'd take a week or so which could be
expensive
um
yeah that's definitely i just don't know
how much it would
it would uh it would take technically to
build something like that but
that would honestly speed up my process
the most out of anything
and also i think would be valuable to
other people even just not
with catalyst just to use for their own
purposes well and do you think but i
mean if you had a tool tour you're on
your phone you're on a website
do you really want to do that data entry
on your
on your phone or do you
want to just save it for later and do it
later the problem with saving it for
later is i have like 2 000 tabs
and trying to go through them now would
take weeks whereas like
if i find something and i'm like i
already looked through it it's already
in my head like what it is
um that process if i streamlined it
could take me like 30 seconds that would
then
be forever catalogued in this knowledge
base that also like
you know hopefully thousands of other
people can can get
use out of um so that tagging i think
the time spent to do that tagging
at the time of finding the site just
like is
game theoretically is more valuable to
do it there and then
for that person and for everyone else
who's involved in the network
and so i would obviously want people to
be rewarded for doing
that tagging whether that was like
financially paid like i
i have a pool of money that i'm willing
to like put for the first
round of comment sharing basically and
like anyone who contributes to that
comment would basically get a piece of
that
and hopefully if i did find a way to get
some sort of
um you know patreon subscription or
donations
then that would go into that pool um so
that's
that's the kind of idea behind that yeah
yeah we got about
four minutes left um let me throw an
idea out there
now this is once again far future um and
it's
have you heard of did we talk about
murmurations yet
yes i i um i didn't realize it was
the way that birds moved together that's
so cool yeah i tried
that's all i could find but go on so i'm
also thinking that you're doing this
thing to where you're going to a website
saying oh here's the logo
and here's maybe even the descriptive
text so first of all a lot of
websites do have that descriptive text
in
the in metadata on the site so
but it'd be interesting that if you have
a collection tool like you just showed
us
uh and then it logged where on the site
is getting all the data and then have it
weekly
check every website or however often you
want to see whether that's changed
so then it would be constantly that
other thing where we talk about where
things get stale
and then giving websites the ability
just like in immersions to say
to post that information so we know what
the updates are and we know we can grab
it automatically
but have that be optional because people
won't do it but
there are some services out there where
you can go to a website highlight some
text
and it'll check that website and let you
know what it changes
um but you would want to i don't know of
any of those that give an api that you
could integrate into your air table
toward automatically pull it and then
maybe not automatically pull but pull it
so that someone could review it
because if the website doesn't mean it
you don't know that you're getting the
same text but at least you'll know that
that text
that has changed enough that it's gone
and someone can take a look at it
and then yeah and i think also if you do
get some funds
not just have a community where people
get it i mean i guess you could do it
this way too but there's a lot of va's
and
certain countries where it doesn't cost
that much because of the difference in
um
in currencies uh that you could
have just some trained people that go in
and categorize us without too much
expense
so all those options i don't know
i don't know this makes everything more
complex but there's something about like
when you did that
in your web browser there are parts of
it that were way too complex for me in
part like i would look at that and be
like i'm not
there's no way i'm dead entering that
but if i was able to go in
and let's say be like oh i can grab
logos
and spend you know half an hour just
grabbing logos and spend half an hour
you know what i mean just doing the text
i think what bentley's suggesting is a
more ai approach of like we already have
the logo and then it will just keep
updating the logo for that
portion but having that in between where
people who are less tech savvy
can that i can just tag something say
ooh this website looks really cool
someone ought to look at this and
be able to do what i can't do with it
and if it's already repetitive and
someone's already tagged that one it
doesn't care and if it hasn't been
looked at people know to look at it
and people know if they have one
specific skill set like i'd rather just
there's a url i can keep getting logos
all day long no problem especially if
it's not easy and it's just
dragging over it but doing it in
piecemeal so that as
i if you're somebody who can go and do
all of that
great and if you're someone who can just
tag it great and if you're someone who
can
go in and do a bunch of logos we know
that'll be done for all of them and then
having ai go back in and update it would
be great what that sounds like
i always like coming up with seems like
simple solutions but i know
that little web clipper um you can write
little
like scripts to pull things from like
html tags and other things but it's
beyond me so
bentley maybe that's something that we
could at some point take a look at but
yeah i don't know if that i've also
researched open graph which is what
facebook uses to like categorize things
and i know there's a lot of sites that
like
have like type topic like movie length
they have like all those like
sub tabs in in there but i don't know if
you could pull from that
with that web clipper as like a first
step towards that
i love the idea though of um kind of
like being able to go and sync with the
site and pull different things
and i i was gonna yeah i don't know i'm
not techy enough to like really be able
to talk to the people from murmurations
and like understand what's going on
yeah and i can definitely help with that
i you know if i was going to suggest
next steps um is that
the the biggest thing is is with all of
our projects is funding and volunt
funding funding and or volunteers so i
guess it's resources right
you know seeing if yeah so that's really
kind of nut
that we might spend a little time trying
to crack because
everything else we can we can figure if
you have
both of those and what's funny maybe we
need to talk about again either on one
of our friday calls or next saturday is
you know we've tried to build similar
well it has a slight overlap with which
it's we're doing just knowledge commons
for our projects
right um how what's the best way for us
as a group to kind of collaborate
on all this stuff and not duplicate so
right
that's one thing that came up for me as
i was watching that
have you been the only one doing the
data entry so far vincent
it has all that come from you or there
are other people logging in and
contributing as well already uh
right now in the current form because
i've been changing the the tools every
week i've been the main person doing all
the data entry
there are other people who have
contributed to the
the database in bulk and so that's
another thing like
hey i already made a list of all these
things and uh you know i've gotten some
csvs from people of
of data that i've put into it already
okay i'm doing the individual uploading
because i've been changing that
every single week and it would be a
nightmare
yeah the nature of prototypes that's
always fun
um is there any element of sort of
deduplication
built in like on that web clipper if you
go to submit a site that i've already
submitted
does it stop me does it warn me does it
merge them
these are sort of things that i i need
help with kind of automating
airtable has a built-in hadoop function
where you can kind of go in
and like it'll pull up two records that
match the url or the title and you could
you could dupe them and you can also set
up like filters where like
if a new record is submitted and it
matches an existing url then it won't
push to the site
um but that stuff just gets so much more
complicated
and i don't really know how to approach
it yet um because
there's other issues that i haven't got
to come up with i think that's a good
problem to have if people are submitting
the same
the same thing and then kind of like
merging merging them i would assume
would be the best way to kind of go
about that and like give both people
credit
for for helping on it the the easy way
to go about this would be i would say
like when you upload a resource
you can maybe just have a list of all
the other resources so you can say like
hey type in the url like make sure it's
not here i don't know if that's
uh not user-friendly enough but
yeah that's part of if you're doing this
if like if i went on and i did all of
that
and i'm in my little brain that would be
a lot of work more than when you're and
if i knew right away as soon as i
went to clip it with the url that it
would or it was had already been done
and it was maybe just missing some spots
i could fill in those spots
but if if i had to do that all and then
find it was already duplicated i would
never be doing it again
is what is is yeah for my my point of
view
like i learned and did all that whereas
i would absolutely just copy and paste
the url and be like oh somebody did it
cool i don't need to do it
yeah and i work in an industry where i
help sort of people do
did entry and for the most part people
don't check if it already exists
even in tools where it's super easy and
sometimes it'll stop you they still find
ways to bypass sit and add duplicate
information
you know because they're in the middle
of something one of the steps in their
head isn't check to see if it already
exists
it's just like okay i've got this i want
to enter and then move on to the next
step
and i think two jubilees point the first
time either you go to search and the
same thing shows up three times you're
like oh
never mind or if you submit it and do
all the work and then you
you you found out that you just
submitted the third one and they all
disagree
again that's probably going to be like
oh i'll just use google
yeah no i think if if i were to build or
have a
like an app built where you can like
share to the first thing would be it
would
check if that url exists on the site and
pre-fill
with the existing right where you can
like kind of like add to it
um cool yeah as of right now it's my
mind remembering if i've added a
research which
for a prototype it totally makes sense
right like that's
i i won't have any form of deduplication
in mind for ages but
that sort of that something that like
until i have it i kind of can't bring in
a bunch of people because it gets
unwieldy really fast
yeah yeah i mean i it would be nice to
have other people kind of working on
help
categorizing the data but i think at
this point i need more help making that
process smoother so that other people
actually
want to like like right now if i can
make it easier for me where i'd like
it's seamless for me to do it then at
that point i would feel comfortable with
like opening up for other people
right cool yeah i guess if you're gonna
like purpose build a chrome extension
you could almost have like the icon
change if we know about the current site
so as you're you know going and browsing
in chrome
if you go to some cool um you know
accelerator page you're like oh this is
cool and you you you look at the button
and it has that we don't have that yet
cool i'll go click and start start
adding it if it just did that for every
site you visit
it might be an easy indication on like
oh the site you're on we don't have so
if it's useful
consider yeah
i i think with the chrome yeah i have a
field in air table
which basically is like form url
plus all the information concatenated
like
of that post so it's like an update
post uh url so basically what i would do
is if
if there was if the chrome extension
bookmarked something and it was a
url that existed it would just redirect
you to a pre-filled form where you can
like
edit it right could you do an iframe in
a chrome extension
not sure where i mean you might be able
to like i've used chrome extensions that
when you interact with them in certain
ways it opens up a new tab and then
on that page you probably could or you
might be able to but like i don't think
it like i'm wondering if you could just
embed a form in a chrome extension
i see you mean like use the chrome
extension to like sort of add a frame to
the page like on the top or the side of
the bottom or something
right i'm saying like because i have
it's like air table forms right that
that update the data like that's done if
i could just embed
a form in that air table extension which
is kind of what it is
i don't know if that's like a easy thing
to do i guess
adriel you are also kind of like on the
no code border or do you
do code as well all right before you
guys get into that let's uh
let's say goodbye to youtube because
we're okay yeah it's faster
time all right